GEOFFREY DAGLEY

McKinney, TX | 469-742-1130 | gdagley@gmail.com

https://geoffreydagley.com https://github.com/gdagley https://linkedin.com/in/gdagley

DEVELOPER | LEADER | INNOVATOR

25+ years of experience developing for all aspects and scales of web and mobile applications, leading remote teams building massively distributed applications, and innovating with over 75 patents for new and upcoming ideas. Involved in all stages of the software development life cycle, both in startups and in enterprise environments, providing direction with new and emerging open source technologies, including

LANGUAGES DART, JAVASCRIPT, RUBY, JAVA, OBJ-C, C#, PYTHON, LUA, SQL, UML

MOBILE AWS AMPLIFY, FLUTTER, IOS, ANDROID, UNITY, CORONA, IONIC, RUBYMOTION

WEB AWS AMPLIFY, REACT, RUBY ON RAILS, JQUERY, ANGULAR, HTML, CSS

ANDROID, JAVA, SPRING

DATABASES AWS DYNAMODB, POSTGRES, MYSQL, REDIS, MEMCACHE

AWS, MAC OS X, IOS, ANDROID, WINDOWS, UNIX



EXPERIENCE

Capital One

Director, Software Engineering

Feb 2022 - Present

- Successfully managed multiple agile teams remotely, overseeing the development and growth of Capital One's Leads Navigator and Showroom products, utilizing Agile methodologies through the entire software development life cycle (SDLC).
- Developed highly efficient and self-sufficient teams that delivered new features while ensuring adherence to Capital One's high software and infrastructure standards.
- Collaborated closely with product partners to define and prioritize product and technical initiatives, ensuring alignment with business goals and objectives.
- Actively involved in the technical interviewing process, serving as both an interviewer and mentor to new interviewers, to ensure the selection of top talent.

Capital One

Sr Manager, Software Engineering

Feb 2020 - Feb 2022

- Led multiple teams of engineers through the acquisition of Carvoy.com, and successfully re-implemented Carvoy IP using the Capital One technology stack within 9 months.
- Oversaw the technical growth of Leads Navigator to be used by over 3500 dealerships and \$1B in originations, ensuring seamless integration with existing systems.

Capital One

Lead Software Engineer

Jul 2017 - Feb 2020

- Part of a research and development team exploring new technologies in financial services, identifying innovative solutions to drive business growth.
- Developed a proof-of-concept augmented reality iOS app that used machine learning to create a unique car buying experience, which
 was showcased at SxSW 2018 and later released as the Capital One Auto Navigator app, showcasing technical and innovation skills.
- Developed new ways to enhance the Auto Navigator search experience, continuously improving the user experience.

Magic Leap

Programmer

Apr 2016 - Jul 2017

- Prototyped a variety of XR experiences for the Magic Leap One using agile methodologies to ensure a streamlined development process
- Built a prototyping tool to randomly generate rooms for testing AR experiences, which helped to identify and fix issues early in the SDLC.

FuzzyCube Software

Programmer

May 2014 - Apr 2016

• Developed and launched the mobile game "Tap It Big" on iOS and Android using the Unity cross-platform toolset, applying best

- practices in software development and project management to meet the launch deadline of 11/2015.
- Led the development of the backend services for an unreleased cross-platform game, including leaderboards, friends, and in-app purchases, using Ruby to create REST-like APIs.

Newtoy/Zynga With Friends Lead, Backend Services

May 2010 - Jun 2013

- Managed a remote team of developers that scaled the With Friends Backend Service using Ruby on Rails to support 10M+ daily users
 playing With Friends games
- Coordinated the migration of the service to two different data centers within a year due to the Zynga acquisition, with minimal disruption to players.
- Grew the With Friends Backend Service from initially supporting Chess and Words to being able to support any new With Friends style game that Zynga wanted to develop, driving significant revenue growth.

McKinney Station

Owner May 2010 - Jun 2013

- Successfully updated a set of existing flash card apps for iOS and provided Android versions of the apps using the cross-platform Corona toolset for Knowsys.
- Co-organized the Dallas Ruby User Group from 2006 to 2011, coordinating speakers, maintaining website, and facilitating community
 activities for Dallas Rubyists, such as the Ruby/Open Spaces track at Dallas Techfest 2009.
- Developed and deployed the entire Ruby on Rails application for StagingTracks.com to connect model railroaders with area clubs, local shops, and upcoming shows, which receives 7500+ visitors a month.
- Built an automated test suite using RSpec for ROOV.com and provided development support during final push to deployment for Beta release.
- Migrated PHP based prospect management application to Ruby on Rails for the 7-R Ranch Internal Prospect Management application, completely RSpec driven development with Selenium based functional tests for the browser.
- Developed a Ruby on Rails trip planner to compare the cost of driving, flying commercial, and chartering a flight using Google Maps for trip mapping and geocoding for WedgeTravel.com.
- Applied look and feel from Photoshop mockups to a functioning Ruby on Rails application and implemented various aspects of the navigation system and catalog for SchoolBates.com.

Relevance, Inc.

Programmer

Jun 2007 - May 2009

- One of two primary developers to build, test, and deploy the community site for TradeKing.com, featuring custom blog, forum, and feed reader engines to tie back to their trading platform.
- One of two primary developers to build a new product for Essi Systems called 21 DayClub.com, which includes tools for personal change management and personal assessments for evaluating.
- One of two primary developers to build an online classified system for radio stations in markets across the US for Fizmo.com

Southwest Airlines

Contract Software Developer

Jun 2006 - Apr 2007

- Designed and implemented business services for Service Oriented Architecture(SOA), including Refunds and Group Deposit applications, using best practices in SDLC to ensure high-quality delivery.
- Automated testing using JUnit to verify test cases defined in design documents, including using mock objects to test interfaces when component implementation did not exist, to ensure software quality and efficiency.
- Used an IDL(Interface Definition Language) to define business service definitions, streamlining the communication process between different components of the system.

EDS

Contract Software Developer

Nov 2005 - Aug 2006

- Designed and implemented a new web-based application for MCI for provisioning virtual trunks, which included overall architecture of web-tier of the application and integration with existing server architecture.
- Jumpstarted a team of 5 developers that did not have any prior experience developing Java Struts web applications, using effective communication and leadership skills to ensure a smooth transition.

Navigator Systems

Contract Software Developer

Aug 2005 - Nov 2006

• Designed and implemented enhancements to web-based sales applications for FritoLay, which included resolving existing defects and providing performance enhancements to the applications.

ZMS Technologies, Inc.

Software Engineer

Nov 2004 - Aug 2005

Architected and implemented a Java WebStart fleet planning solution for small businesses, providing a development environment that
included a one-step build-test-deploy process, continuous integration builds and nightly builds, bug tracking system, and development
wiki for documentation, demonstrating expertise in software engineering and SDLC.

- Researched and provided direction for technologies(Spring, Hibernate, WebStart) used in the current development of transportation management software, demonstrating expertise in software integration and technical leadership.
- Analyzed, maintained, and enhanced components for transportation management J2EE web application based on customer requirements, demonstrating expertise in software development and problem-solving skills.

Nextlet, Inc.

Software Engineer

Jul 2004 - Oct 2004

• Analyzed, maintained, and enhanced components for J2EE web application based on customer bug reports and enhancement requests, demonstrating expertise in software maintenance and customer support.

Parago, Inc

Application Architect

Oct 2002 - Jun 2004

- Analyzed and designed components for mission-critical, enterprise-wide J2EE web application.
- Led a team of 5 developers in building a Check Fulfillment component, which involved developing a web client interface based on discussions with the business owners, followed by deploying and performance tuning the application on JBoss application server.

Batky-Howell, Inc.

Instructor

May 2001 - Oct 2002

- Taught Java/J2EE programming classes for large customers including Boeing, MCI Worldcom, Nielsen Media Research, and Sprint, demonstrating expertise in both software development and teaching.
- Developed courseware for new and developing technologies like SOAP and Web Services, showcasing a willingness to stay up-to-date with the latest industry developments.
- Edited and revised courseware as versions of software became available, including J2EE 1.2 and Java 1.3, highlighting a dedication to ongoing learning and professional development.



★ PROJECTS

Open Source - github.com/gdagley

Various source projects on github.com through the years

mibipi.com

2013-09 - Present

- Read through the Bible app available on iOS and Android
 - Originally written with RubyMotion for iOS
 - Later updated and released on iOS and Android using the Ionic cross platform toolset
 - Recently rewritten in Flutter and Dart using Bloc for state management
 - Used AWS and Serverless Framework to optimize online retrieval of daily reading contnet

31DayPrayerChallenge.com

2009-09 - Present

Mobile apps based on the 31 Day Prayer Challenges from mikeleake.net

- The original iOS apps were built with RubyMotion and the Android apps were built with Java
- Recently rewritten in Flutter and Dart using Bloc for state management

CatechizeMe 2009-09 - Present

Mobile app to encourage learning church doctrine through catechisms. Launched: 11/2012

- The iOS app was built with RubyMotion and the Android app was build with Java
- Rewritten in Flutter and Dart using Bloc for state management



EDUCATION

Texas A&M University - College Station, TX

Sep 1994 - May 1998

Bachelor of Science in Aerospace Engineering



SPEAKING

Scaling With Friends, Rails Conf 2011

2011

Scaling With Friends, Dallas Big Ruby 2013

2013

Failing With Friends, Dallas Crosstrain 2014

2014